let's talk about how AI is transforming
the legal industry if you've always
wondered what it would be like to have
an AI lawyer at your fingertips or a
tool that helps your legal team write
out documents assesses risk analyzes
Clauses and generates case summaries I
made this video for you legal is one of
the most powerful AI niches to come out
of this revolution many of these tools
are so powerful that big law firms are
actually restructuring their workflows
just to integrate them so chat gbt was
released in November of 2022 and just
look at this insane surve in searches
for AI lawyer soon after that now that
did decrease in the following year
mainly because AI startups really just
needed time to bootstrap and to solve
these problems but we're seeing
continued growth now and I predict that
more of these tools will grow and emerge
in 2025 so if you're looking for tools
to help you win your next case stick
around if you a friend or family member
is an attorney and they're looking for a
trending legal AI startup with 300%
growth in Just 2 years check this out
it's called Robin AI Robin is an AI
company that uses our artificial
intelligence to speed up the process of
reviewing and managing legal documents
their Tech makes it way easier to
understand these docs it also automates
a bunch of these really long and mundane
tasks so legal teams can save a lot of
time and money Robin AI has three key
modules for contract customization draft
review and query the draft module lets
you create contracts from pre-built
templates which already massively speeds
up the process with review you can edit
and negotiate contracts with AI assisted
live suggestions BAS based on customized
negotiating playbooks basically it just
makes sure that you don't miss anything
in the jumble the query module gives you
a searchable contract library that
allows you to quickly find and analyze
relevant Provisions across multiple
documents so whether you have your own
practice or you're part of a big firm
Robin AI has a plan for you for bigger
firms their platform can hire a large
volume of contracts plus they make
contract review 80% faster than
traditional methods so let's quickly
recap a few of the tasks that they're
going to take off your plate automated
Drafting and customizing ation using AI
customizable templates designed by legal
experts real-time suggestions and
recommendations during contract
negotiation AI power Clause
identification and risk assessment
collaborative contract editing and
version tracking and more reviews do
seem mixed but overall positive citing
document accuracy time-saving and risk
assessment that said it's still as
important to review everything because
the tech isn't quite there yet where we
have 100% confidence that it just
replaces all of these jobs they do have
a free version but right now their pro
version is at 100 per month they've
already stacked over $43 million in
series B funding and given their
relatively low search volume I would say
this one is definitely set to continue
scaling in 2025 so keep an eye out
here's a legal AI platform with over
1,000% Search growth in the past 2 years
alone let's talk about Harvey Ai No I'm
not talking about the guy from Suits
basically it's a generative AI platform
for big legal firms and it's able to
analyze contracts identify Clauses and
extract important terms and conditions
their overall goal is to help law firms
boost efficiency reduce risk and
allocate more time to higher value tasks
things like building client
relationships and giving strategic legal
advice in a nutshell it takes care of a
lot of the busy work so the lawyers can
actually move faster and with more
agility let's take a look at a few more
features here faster identification of
relevant Clauses statutes and precedents
automated contract summaries and
flagging potential issues multi language
support for analyzing Clauses across
different jurisdictions assistance in
drafting and revising legal documents
reducing that manual work this one's
pretty cool Predictive Analytics for
forecasting case outcomes and assessing
risk enhanced legal research
capabilities providing relevant case law
and statutes quickly it's even got a
secure project workspace for analyzing
protected documents while Robin AI works
for a variety of different clients
Harvey is mainly targeted at larger
firms so let's talk about reviews and
testimonials Allan and overy which is
now ano Sheeran One of the world's
largest firms had 3,500 lawyers test
Harvey AI by asking over 40,000
questions about day-to-day work the head
of their markets Innovation said I have
never seen anything like Harvey Harvey
can work in multiple languages and
across diverse practice areas delivering
unprecedented efficiency and
intelligence in our trial we saw some
amazing results after scrolling around
their site it looks like pricing is
customized to the firm but if you're a
big firm this definitely seems like the
best option around Harvey AI has stacked
over 200 million in series C funding and
considering their list of pretty
impressive clients I would say this one
is set to to continue growing in 2025
are you looking for an AI Legal
Assistant that can read analyze and
summarize legal documents at a postgrad
level if so let's talk about case text
case text was recently acquired by
Thompson Rutters for an insane $650
million co-council their gen AI Legal
Assistant is now the pretty face of the
company it leverages GPT to automate
legal tasks like Doc review legal
research deposition prep and contract
analysis it does this by combining
natural language processing and Boolean
search which is basically a mathematical
system that says variables can either
have two answers a one or a zero a true
or a false and this is really important
when it comes to Legal applications
because AI can sometimes default to the
easiest possible solution or even
hallucinate when you need something
really concrete with a bunch of
pre-existing rules in place for anybody
who uses AI regularly you know how
frustrating it can be to have something
hallucinate like for example I have
tried to get stats about specific
Industries using AI before and sometimes
it just makes the stats up and then when
I ask the AI hey provide the actual
Source it says oh I can't do that and I
say why it's because oh I just
fabricated that result so you can
imagine in a legal situation there's no
room for anything like this and that's
why this combination of natural language
processing and Boolean search is so
important let's say you've got a
deposition coming up just provide all
the info about your deponent and it'll
give you all these really great pointed
questions it also makes Doc review an
interactive and really simple process to
mitigate risk you can also upload all
your documents and it'll scan through
everything to try and find potential
conflicts they core assistant clocks in
at 225 per month with customized pricing
for larger firms now I went looking on
Reddit to see what people actually think
I dug into reviews and blog posts and it
looks like they do still have some
improvements to make but overall people
are happy with the price the citation
check and their Integrations now overall
this one has had strong and steady
growth over the past 5 years and I hope
that they can keep that momentum going
post acquisition and grow even further
this year so let's find out let's look
at a specialized AI Legal Assistant with
almost 9,000 Search growth in the past 2
years alone and that is Paxton AI legal
research which normally takes dozens if
not hundreds of hours can now be
shortened down to just a few minutes
sounds too good to be accurate right
well Paxton boasts a 94% accuracy rate
with its legal research tool I mean the
whole platform was created out of this
demand for faster more efficient
research and drafting it excels at
documents drafting with legal precedence
integrated comprehensive document
analysis AI assisted contextual research
and the overall ability to deepen and
expand on your existing work like Robin
Paxton is great for all firms big and
small for the smaller firms it's great
because it provides a lot of research
ability without all the paralal help
while digging into the reviews on this
one I found one user that said I had a
friend who needed a release and a waiver
for her dance studio with a large
customer base of children I researched
the applicable release laws for minors
in my jurisdiction and then asked Paxton
to draft a waiver that complied with
those laws I had it done and sent in 20
minutes now if you're an independent
lawyer or a student this one is great
because they do have a student option at
just 25 per month and if you're a small
firm their Pro Plan starts at a pretty
reasonable 159 per month they've already
stacked 6 mil in seed funding and given
their Search growth I would say this one
is definitely set to continue scaling so
check them out today that's all for
today I hope you enjoyed this deep dive
into legal AI tools we're are going to
keep monitoring this Niche to Bubble Up
any new startups and platforms that have
insane growth and applications for both
big and small firms if you have any
questions about these or you'd like us
to analyze a specific trend let's chat
in the comments below thank you and I'll
see you in our next video